There are more than 30 health
insurance companies in India. In such a situation, if you
are confused about
which health insurance plan can be best for you and your family,
then in today's video I am going to
tell you about the top five health insurances. We will discuss
all the features, benefits,
USPs and unique benefits of those five health insurances.
Also,
in the last of the video, I will
rank those five plans on the basis of their claim settlement, their
features, benefits and premium.
So stay tuned with this video till the end.
Hello friends, I am Ashutosh your
personal finance co. Let's start the video.
The plans I have selected are
IIC Lord at
hdfc.com Care
9.50. However, the claim settlement ratio is quite
misleading and we
cannot select any health insurance on its basis.
It can be manipulated in many ways. There is
a reliable ratio, Income Ratio.
Talking about IR, the income ratio
of IIC Lord  78.8
ICICI Lombard 9500 Hospitals
ADFC ERGO 13000 Plus Hospitals TA
IG 11000 Plus Hospitals Nava Bupa 10000
Plus Hospital & Care 11400 Plus
Hospitals However, we are not concerned with the
all-India coverage list of any insurance company.
We need to see whether the
hospitals around us where we can go for treatment are
covered by that insurance company or
not. Talking about some unique points of these insurance plans
or their US, the
most
unique selling point of III Lord Elevate is 100% cumulative
bonus every year. In this plan, we get a 100%
bonus every year. So, if you have a
policy of Rs 10 lakh and you renew it for the next 10 years,
it will become Rs 1 crore. If you
renew it for 20 years, it will become Rs 2 crore.
Apart from this, this plan also covers hypertension, diabetes,
cholesterol, asthma and obesity
without any waiting period.
Unlimited Restoration:
This plan also offers the option of unlimited claim
amount once in a lifetime. This
means that you can make a claim
for an unlimited amount once in a lifetime.
Whether your policy is for Rs 10
lakh or Rs 20 lakh, even if the claim is
for Rs 1 crore, you
can pay a claim for an unlimited amount. The next unique benefit is the
Unlimited Sum Assured option. This plan
offers sum assured options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore. However, there's
also an unlimited sum assured option. This
option offers
no limit on the sum assured. This is a unique
benefit available only with this plan.
Additionally, you also get optional maternity cover
and a credit score discount.
This is also a very unique benefit. If you have a
good credit score, you can get a
significant discount with ADAC ORG
Optima Secure.  Talking about unique benefits, the
most important unique
benefit is the Secure Benefit, which
provides 2x coverage. This means that if we have
taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh, it
covers us for Rs 20 lakh from day one. Apart from this, there is
Unlimited Restoration and Plus Benefit, which
covers non-payable consumables in-built
without any rider.
Talking about the unique benefits of Medicare Premier,
its most unique benefit is that it
covers OPD for two years. There
is a limit of Rs 5,000 to Rs 15,000 for different sums.
Apart from this, most health
insurance plans exclude dental treatment,
but this plan
also covers in-patient dental treatment for two years.
Apart from this, consumer
items are also covered in this plan.
Hearing aids are also covered in this plan. There is also an
inbuilt maternity benefit, which
covers us during the waiting period of four years.
And we do not have to pay any separate premium for that. There
is also an inbuilt global cover
for plant hospitalization and benefits for high-end
diagnostics
are also available in this plan. Talking about the unique benefits of NPA,
its most important benefit is
Lock the Clock. In every health insurance,
our premium increases in the bracket of 5 years
and some plans also
increase our premium every year along with our age.
But in this plan, we
get a benefit that until we do not make our first
claim,
our premium remains the same according to age and does
not increase. Apart from that, there is a benefit
which gives us unlimited restoration. Also, the
restoration in most of the plans is
available from the second claim every year.
But the restoration benefit of this plan gets activated for the
life time after the first claim.
Along with this, there is a
booster benefit which gives us coverage up to 10
times. So, if you have a sum assured of Rs
10 lakh  If you have a policy, you
get a bonus of ₹10 lakh every year, which
can go up to 10 times to reach 1 CR.
Apart from this, your policy has the option of deductible.
Most insurance plans
cover hospitalization beyond 24 hours,
but this plan
also covers hospitalization beyond two hours if there is any
active treatment. Also, in this plan,
we get a disease management rider
which covers hypertension and diabetes
from day one. Talking about the unique benefits of Care Supreme,
we get a
cumulative bonus of ₹500 per year. This means that if you have a
policy of ₹10 lakh, then you can also get a cumulative bonus of ₹50 lakh in it.
This plan also covers a cumulative bonus without any waiting period.
Also, in this plan, we
can reduce other pre-aggregates.
Talking about the minimum and maximum entry age,
in all the plans, the
minimum entry age for a dependent child is 90 days. The
minimum entry age for an adult is 18 years.
Talking about the maximum entry age, there is
no maximum entry age in ICICI Lord Elevate, ADFC, Optima Secure, and Care Supreme.
You can enroll at any age, even after 65.
In IG Medicare Premier and Niva Bupa Aspire, the maximum entry age is 65
years. Talking about the sum insured options,
in ICICI Elevate, you get a sum assured option of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore.
Apart from that, we
also get an unlimited sum assured option. Sum assured options of Rs 5 lakh
to Rs 2 crore are available in Optima Secure, Rs 5 lakh
to Rs 3 crore in Medicare Premier, Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore in
Aspire, Rs 3 lakh to Rs 1 crore and Rs
5 lakh to Rs 1 crore in Care Supreme.
Talking about the room category,
in ICICI Elevate, there is a
capping of single private AC room for Rs 5 lakh policy. There is
also a capping of single private AC room in Rs 10 lakh and above policy,
but
we can remove it with a rider. So,
effectively, we can assume that above Rs 10 lakh policy will be eligible for the policy.  There is
no capping in the policy.
Apart from that, there is no capping on room rent room category wise in the other four plans.
AYUSH
treatment is covered up to the sum in all the plans.
Talking about pre and post hospitalization,
ICICI Elevate covers 90 days and
180 days, Optima Secure 60 and 180 days,
Medicare Premier 60 and 90 days, Niva Bappa
Aspire 60 and 180 days and Care Supreme
60 and 180 days. Day care treatment is covered
up to the sum in all the plans.
Organ donor is covered up to the sum in all the plans.
Medical hospitalization
is covered up to the sum in all the plans.
Talking about home care treatment, it is
not available in ICICI Elevate, it
is available in Optima Secure, it is
also not available in Medicare Premier, it is available in Aspire
and it is not available in Care Supreme.
Talking about restoration benefit, it is
aaaaa long  Unlimited
restoration benefit is available in Daily Wait but there is a
waiting period of 45 days for meeting the same person.
With fear, we can avail one unlimited restoration
benefit which is
for both related and unrelated illnesses, meaning there is
no waiting period for the same person with the same illness. In IG Medicare Premier,
once-in-a-policy-year restoration
is available, in which there is
a waiting period of 45 days for the same person with the same illness, which is
a very negative point.
Unlimited restoration is available in Niva Bupa Aspire
and is
for both related and unrelated illnesses. There is
no capping for the same personal same illness.
Unlimited restoration is also available in Supreme and there is
no capping for the same person with the same illness.
Available for both related and unrelated illnesses. Talking about No Claim Bonus or
Cumulate Bonus,
there is a guaranteed cumulate bonus in III Elevate.  It is 20 per
plan maximum up to 100%. Apart from that we
get an optional benefit of Power Booster
in which we get a cumulative bonus of 100%
every year hdfcergo.com
maximum up to 100% n p In Air we
get Booster benefit which
gives us a bonus of up to 10 times in which
our remaining sum assured gets carried forward.
In Supreme we get a
cumulative bonus of 50 per plan maximum up to 100%.
Apart from that we get an optional cumulative bonus
Super which
gives us a cumulative bonus of up to 500. Talking about road ambulance,
up to sum assured is covered in all the plans except Medicare Premier.
In Medicare Premier we get claim benefit on 5000.
Air Ambulance
up to sum assured in III Elevate
hdfc0000001 Year & Care Supreme gets
air ambulance benefits up to sum assured.
Free health checkup ICI Lord
Elevate and Care  Free health
checkup is not available in Supreme, we have to
select it as an option. Apart from that,
free health checkup is available in all the three plans.
Wellness discount up to 20% is not available in IIC Lord. It is
also not available in Medicare Premier.
Wellness discount up to 30%
is available in Nip Aspen Care Supreme. Modern treatment
up to sum shot is covered in all the plans without any capping.
Second medical opinion is
not available in Elevate. It is available once per person
in Optima Secure. It is
available in Medicare Premier.
Unlimited times is available in Niva Bappa Spa. It is
not available in End Care Supreme. E-
consultation is available unlimited times in all the plans.
This maternity cover is available with hdfcergo.com.
Optional maternity cover is available in Lord Elevate, in
which a waiting period of 2 years will be available,
which can be reduced to 1 year with a rider.  In
which we get benefits of
up to Rs 1 lakh on 10 per sum,
maternity benefit is not available in Optima Secure.
Inbuilt maternity is available in Medicare Premier, in
which a waiting period of four years will be
applicable. Inbuilt
maternity is also available in NPAY, in which a
waiting period of nine months will be applicable and its
coverage will also depend on the sum shot. There is
no maternity available in Supreme.
New born baby cover is also available in IIC.
Cover is available in K Supreme, but not in Supreme.
Talking about waiting periods, an
initial waiting period of 30 days will be applicable in all the plans,
which is
common industry wise. Apart from that, a
waiting period of two years will be applicable for slow growing diseases.
Pre-establishing
health insurance is a very complex situation,
in such a situation, as important as it is to select the best health insurance, it is equally
important that we get the health insurance right.  From
where are you purchasing because after
sales services play a
very important role in health insurance. In such a situation,
many times we
purchase the policy from the online portal due to some discount, but
then we have to face trouble for the claim.
When we make an online purchase, we have
tele callers who do
not have on-ground experience of the products or the claim center. Or
we will have a customer care number and
customer care email ID. In such a situation,
if there is any dispute, then we have to face a
lot of trouble.
In health insurance in India,
we see some issue or problem in almost 60% of claims. In such a situation,
if you have an experienced advisor
who has experience in
claim center,
then your health insurance
journey becomes quite good.
Friends, if you want to purchase your policy with me
or
want to discuss your health insurance, then whatsapp2 on the
number given below,
almost 22 23 optional.  There are
benefits, which means that to
keep the premium low, they have made almost many
benefits optional.
In Unlimited Restoration, whose premium is
quite low, you
can also consider it an inbuilt feature. Apart from that, there are Critical
Illness Hospital Cash, Personal Accident and
Optima Well Being which is an OPD rider. There are
no optional benefits in Medicare Premier, which means that they have
kept everything inbuilt, that is why its
premium is a bit high.
In B Air, there is Fast Forward Future Ready
Cash Back Safeguard Plus Well Consult which is
an OPD rider, apart from that there are Personal
Accident Hospital Deductible and DM
Rider which covers hypertension and diabetes from day one.
In Supreme, there are optional benefits like Cumet Bonus,
Super Annual Health Checkup, Air Ambulance
Claim Shield, Instant Cover, PD Waiting
Period Reduction.
Friends, I have given the
details link on all these plans, you will find it on the ID card or on the
end screen at the end of the video,
or you can also check by going to the playlist.
I have listed all the benefits for them.  The
benefits have been discussed in detail.
Talking about the person-wise premium,
person-wise premium
is available in all the plans but there is no zone-wise payment. There are
four people in Elevate, two people in Optime Inc.,
three people in Ta Ezee,
four people in Niva Pop Air and two people in Keso Prem.
Talking about the premium, for the premium
I have taken the example of a 30-year-old couple with two kids, in
which I have
included some necessary riders like
consumer covers and joumet bonus etc.
Talking about the premium in ICICI Elevate,
almost 26000 hdfc0001869
and Niva Bupa Aspire Fourth and Care
Supreme Fifth.
I have given the first rank to ICICI Lord Elevate because its
features are quite unique. Premium-wise it is also
quite cost-effective. Along with this, IIC
Lord is also very good in claim settlement. It is a
very old company and the
claim of  The settlement experience is quite
good hdfcergo.com
[music] There are
no advanced features. In such a situation, if you are a
person who does not care much about the premium, then
hdfcergo.com
is quite good for you with higher coverage. In such a situation, if you
purchase a policy with higher coverage of Rs 50 lakh, 1 crore,
2 crore, then the policy of Ta Ease can be a very
good option for you, but
with a lower time shot, I would not recommend it.
Niva Papa Aspire is a very unique plan, it has
many unique features, but still
I have given it the fourth rank because
somewhere I feel that their claim
settlement service is not like the top three plans, there is a
bit of delay, they
do a lot of over-evaluation, that is why
I did not give it a rank in the top three.
Care got the fifth rank only because of its features and
its premium.
Its premium is quite low. But still I would
recommend Care only in the last place. If there is a very
high budget issue, then only
go for Care.  Because Service Wise Care is
not a very good or very reliable brand,
friends, if this video is good for you and the
information is
sure to sell you, if
you want to see more such information videos, then
you must subscribe to the channel,
friends, that's all in today's video,
see you in the next video, thank you.